<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Theory on Krishna Bhamidipati</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/theory/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Theory on Krishna Bhamidipati</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Thoughts on Headphone Amplifiers - Should I Get One?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/audio/2019/thoughts-on-headphone-amplifiers/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/audio/2019/thoughts-on-headphone-amplifiers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should I get one? Probably not for 300 Ohm headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-analysis-of-impedance&#34;&gt;An Analysis of Impedance
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below is a conversation I had with a friend who asked me if I used a DAC for my HD 650 mixing headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have a DAC (Apogee One) and was experimenting between using it and my MacBook/iMac&amp;rsquo;s output. Kinda can&amp;rsquo;t hear a differece yet in audio quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output impedance (of the computer/audio jack) must always be lower than the consumer&amp;rsquo;s (headphone&amp;rsquo;s) impedance. This priciple also true in live sound: when plugging a mic into a mixer, the mic&amp;rsquo;s impedance must be lower than the mixer&amp;rsquo;s receiving impedance—otherwise you use a DI box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule of thumb for this ratio is a factor of 8. Most consumer headphones have an impedance of 16-32 ohms, so the output impedance of the MBP&amp;rsquo;s/iMac&amp;rsquo;s jack is probably 2-4 ohms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the ratio is not safe—suppose the MBP jack had an output impedance of 10 ohms—then &lt;em&gt;the frequency response will be altered&lt;/em&gt; in the headphones. This could lead to a different spatial response/altered EQ/etc. and depends on the actual headphone design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, the HD 650 has a nominal impedance of 300 Ohms — so it&amp;rsquo;s ratio is 100x! Quite safe from distortion there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you/I will notice is that for the same volume setting on the laptop, the volume will be sofer on the HD650s — because of the nearly 100x impedance ratio. It requires more power to drive it. But as long as it&amp;rsquo;s loud enough, I think you will be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi end mixing headphones have high impedances for the same reason high quality guitar mics have high impedances — they have more coils in the wire, allowing for a better high frequency response. Having the high impedance also makes them conistent—no matter what they&amp;rsquo;re plugged into, they easily meet the rule of thumb of 8x, so the sound will be identical with no distortion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headphone amps work the other way: they basically create a near zero output impedance so that no matter what headphones you use, there will be no distortion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-reading&#34;&gt;Additional Reading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/02/headphone-amp-impedance.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/02/headphone-amp-impedance.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/02/gain-and-headphone-ampsdacs.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/02/gain-and-headphone-ampsdacs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
